## Luciano Augusto Marchezan de Paula

Linz - Austria

+43 67763957341

<u>lucianomarchezan94@gmail.com</u> Scholar:

https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=26yB7xkAAAAJ

#### **SUMMARY**

Has experience in Computer Science, focusing on Software Engineering. Graduated as Software Engineer at Universidade Federal do Pampa (UNIPAMPA) - Campus Alegrete. Currently doing a Master Degree in Software Engineering at Universidade Federal do Pampa - Campus Alegrete.

Working for the past 4 years at the Laboratory of Empirical Studies in Software Engineering (LESSE) as a researcher. Current researching Software Product Line with focus in Re-engineering.

English Proficiency obtained in TOEFL exam. Graduated in English as Second Language at IIT (Illinois Institute of Technology - CHICAGO - EUA) Participated of CsF (Science without Borders) program from 2013 to 2014.

### **EDUCATION**

# Instituto Federal Farroupilha, IF-Farroupilha, Brazil. — Secondary Education .

MAR 2009 - DEC 2011

# Universidade Federal do Pampa, UNIPAMPA, Brazil — Graduation In Software Engineering

MAR 2012 - DEC 2018

Advisor: Elder de Macedo Rodrigues.

Final Project: PAxSPL: a Feature Retrieval Process for Software Product Line Re-engineering. Available online at:

http://dspace.unipampa.edu.br:8080/jspui/bitstream/riu/3335/1/Luciano

Marchezan%202018.pdf

## Universidade Federal do Pampa, UNIPAMPA, Brazil — Professional Master Studies In Software Engineering

MAR 2019 - JUL 2020

Advisor: Elder de Macedo Rodrigues.

Final Project: PAxSPLv4: a Tool-Supported Re-engineering Process for

SPL.

### **SKILLS**

Research skills developed during 4+ years of research experience at the Laboratory of Empirical Studies in Software Engineering.

Programming skills acquired from many courses during graduation and masters: JAVA, PHP, JS, Dart, HTML, CSS, Python and C#.

Skills related to development frameworks: Laravel, Flutter, Firebase, Primefaces, Eclipse Modeling Framework.

Modeling skills: UML, ER, feature models, product line architecture.

#### **AWARDS**

2019 - Best paper from the Masters/PhD track - ERES 2019, III Software Engineering Regional School.

2019 - Student with the most outstanding performance in the Software Engineering Masters Program at Universidade Federal do Pampa.

2018 - Student with the most outstanding performance of the Graduates from the Software Engineering Undergraduate

### **PROJECTS**

# PAxSPLv4: a Tool-Supported Re-engineering Process for SPL. — Masters Project

MAR 2017 - JUL 2018

PAxSPLv4, improves aspects of earlier versions, including a web-based supporting tool. Results available at:

https://sol.sbc.org.br/index.php/eres/article/view/8506

# PAxSPL: A feature retrieval process for software product line reengineering — Final Graduation Project

MAR 2017 - JUL 2018

PAXSPL, a process that provides support to prepare, assemble and execute feature retrieval throughout the analysis of product artifacts, documentation and team experiences. Results available at: https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/spe.2707

# Thoth: A Web-based Tool to Support Systematic Reviews — Research Project

Out 2019 - Present

Development of an open-source web-based tool for supporting Systematic Reviews. Results available at:

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/8870160/

### Model Based Testing (MBT) — Research Project

NOV 2016 - Present

The objective of this project is to investigate new models, tools, and processes that may support and automate the MBT process. Results available at:

https://digital-library.theiet.org/content/journals/10.1049/iet-sen.2015.0

## **Domain Specific Languages For Modeling Performance Tests** — Research Project

MAR 2017 - Present

Development of two DSLs (graphical and textual) for modeling performance tests for web applications.

## **Model Based Testing for Self-adaptive Systems** — Research Project

Out 2019 - Present

Development of a DSL (graphical or textual) for modeling and generating test cases for self-adaptive systems.

Course at Universidade Federal do Pampa awarded by the Brazilian Computer Society.

2018- Student with the most outstanding performance in the Software Engineering Undergraduate Course at Universidade Federal do Pampa.

2016 - Student with the most outstanding performance in the Software Engineering Undergraduate Course at Universidade Federal do Pampa.

2014- Dean's List Certificate, Illinois Institute of Technology School of Applied Technology.

2014- Recognition Award for IPRO Day Track 5, SAT/INTM Brazilian Scientific Mobility Projects at Illinois Institute of Technology School of Applied Technology.

#### **LANGUAGES**

English: Comprehends Well, Speaks Well, Reads Well, Writes Well (TOEFL-IBT Score: 105).

**Spanish**: Comprehends Reasonably, Speaks Little, Reads Reasonably, Writes Little.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **GreenWays2Go,** Chicago, Illinois - USA — Summer *Internship*

JUN 2014 - AUG 2014

A web platform was developed, including web page (<a href="http://greenways2go.com/">http://greenways2go.com/</a>), profiles on social networks such as LinkedIn and Twitter.

### Porthal Sistemas, Alegrete, RS - Brazil — Internship

AUG 2017 - NOV 2017

Software Engineer internship working on systems developed inside the company such as ICodeERP(https://www.icodeerp.com.br/).

### Capataz, Alegrete, RS - Brazil — Part Time

FEB 2019 - PRESENT

Software Engineer developing web and mobile apps for managing cattle at ranches. Company web-site <a href="https://capataz.com.br/">https://capataz.com.br/</a>.